# Debabrata Saha

### Specialist Senior Engineer

Having an experience of 6.7 years with forward-thinking Software Engineer with background working productively in dynamic environments. Fluent in Type and Type programming languages used to develop software within Industry. Proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy.



### **Work History**

### 2022-01 -Current

### **Specialist Software Engineer**

LTI, Kolkata, West Bengal

- Responsible in architechting the application backend in Azure SQL
- Creating views and procedure in SQL for power apps
- Automating various approval flows using power automate
- Involved in requirement gathering and suggesting flexible and user friendly application methodology development

### 2021-05 -2022-01

### Senior Software Engineer

EY, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Responsible in developing Commercial application for internal client of EY
- creating application customized and list view extension in SharePoint framework
- Creating spfx webpart using React is and redux
- Building PCF component for one of esteemed client
- Involved in designing the page using Fluent UI and html css

### 2019-11 -2021-04

### Technology Consultant

PwC, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Designed REST calls using React to streamline user interface performance.
- Maintained high-level expertise in React state



#### **Address**

Kolkata, WB, 700013

#### **Phone**

9874345299

#### E-mail

debabrata18992@gmail.c om

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/debabrata-saha-9a6112a

#### **WWW**

https://debabrata23.gith ub.io/MyWebsiteProfile/



SharePoint online and SPFX

Advanced

SharePoint onpremises

Intermediate

C#

Intermediate

management strategies.

 Designed and implemented dynamic content and web-server applications using best practices.

### 2019-02 - Senior Associate Consultant

2019-10

Mindtree, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Leveraged built-in and hand-crafted development techniques using native SharePoint technologies or designed and developed user-friendly end product for custom solutions.
- Participated in system development life cycle from requirements analysis through system implementation.
- Solved design problems and implemented attractive design using creative methods.
- Involved in SharePoint 2013 support using jQuery and rest API and also involved in end of end redevelopment of a SharePoint 2013 site in sharepoint online using spfx

### 2016-11 -2019-02

### Software Engineer

Acuvate Software PVT LTD, Hyderabad, Telengana

- Solved design problems and implemented attractive design using creative methods.
- Designed and implemented dynamic content and web-server applications using best practices.

### 2016-04 -

### Contractor

2016-10

CMC, Kolkata, West Bengal

 Created optimal technical solutions to user needs with in-depth system analysis.

## **Education**

2008-02 - ICSE : General

2009-02 Lycee - Kolkata

2011-04 - B.Tech : ECE

2015-07 Narula Institute of Technology - Kolkata

### **Powerapps**

Advanced

PowerAutomate online

Advanced

Power virtual agent

Intermediate

React Js

Upper intermediate

Redux

Intermediate

**Javascript** 

Upper intermediate

**CSOM** 

Upper intermediate

**JSOM** 

Upper intermediate

PNP JS

Intermediate

**REST API** 

Intermediate

2010-03 - CBSE 12: Science

2011-02 Apeejay School - Kolkata



2022-06 Microsoft Certified Power Platform fundamental PL

900

**2022-09** Microsoft Certified Power Platform Developer PL 400